Guide to the Program in Comparative Studies on Southern Asia Records, 1964-1977 UA.25.24.0028
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Program in Comparative Studies on Southern Asia records
1964-1977
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Program in Comparative Studies on Southern Asia
UA.25.24.0028
3.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains administrative files of the Program in Comparative Studies on South Asia.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Program in Comparative Studies on South Asia Records were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in March, 2006.
Historical note
Established in 1961 under a Ford Foundation grant to the Commonwealth Studies Center, the Program in Comparative Studies at Duke was set up to facilitate research on, and the training of graduate students in the political, historical, economic, and sociocultural development of Commonwealth countries in Southern Asia. A South Asia center was established in 1963. The program was housed in the International Studies Center and supported and administered through the Office of the Vice Provost for International Studies.
Collection Overview
This collection contains records relating to the administrative activities and courses taught under the auspices of the Program in Comparative Studies on Southern Asia between the mid-1960s and mid-1970s. Included are syllabi, course materials, publicity, financial records, office records, symposium records, grant applications, faculty data, and correspondence.
South Asia -- Study and teaching -- United States; Duke University. Program in Comparative Studies on Southern Asia
- Class Materials, circa 1969-1973; 1
  - Course Syllabi and Course Materials, circa 1969-1973 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Detailed course information, as well as course material packets. Bound.
- Administrative Records, 1964-1977; 2
  - Publicity, South Asia Book News Newsletter, 1964-1977; 2 folders (Box 2)
    Vol. 4, 5, 6, 8, 9, 10 (partial)
  - NDEA Title VI, 1973 January-June (Box 2)
  - Title III Program, 1972 September-November (Box 2)
  - South Asia Committee, Smith, Richard, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Stokes, Eric, 1972 August-September (Box 2)
  - Kessinger, Tom, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Kelley, Allen C., 1972 October (Box 2)
  - Sarc Liason Committee, Harold Gould, 1972 July-December (Box 2)
  - Recommendations, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - NDEA Center Proposal, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - NDEA: Hew Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 2)
  - NDEA Title VI Proposal, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - NDEA Title VI Fellows, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - South Asia Newsletter, 1972 September-October (Box 2)
  - NDEA Technical Report, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Language Instruction, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Submission Fellowships Title VI, NDEA, 1973 (Box 2)
  - NDEA Center Proposal, 1970-1973; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - NDEA Center Proposal, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Finances: Correspondence with Treasurer, 1971-1977 (Box 2)
  - Finances; Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Finances: Financial Reports from Treasurer, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Budgets, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Budget Submission to Committee on International Studies, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Consortium, 1971 (Box 2)
  - COFIS, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Consortium, Summer Language, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Applications, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Symposium, 1971-1972; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Social Science Research Council Questionnaire, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Shonek, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Language and Politics Symposium, Quail Roost Conference Center, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Monographs Reviews, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - NDEA, Title VI Students, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Publicity: Posters and Announcements, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Personnel Appointments, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Publicity, Press Releases, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Reprints, Mailing Lists, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Reviews, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Library, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Monographs, Correspondence re: New Monographs, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Monograph Copyrights, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - NDEA Title VI, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Monograph, Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - ID Course, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - South Asia Committee, Spengler, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Paul C. Winther, 1970 (Box 2)
  - South Asia Committee, 1972 (Box 2)
  - South Asia Committee, General Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - South Asia, General Inquiries, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Virginia South Asia Program, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Visiting Lecturers, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - South Asia Committee Meeting Notices, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Southern Atlantic States Association for South Asian Studies (SASASAS), 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - South Asia Committee: Edward Lavalle, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Questionnaire, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Publicity, 1973 (Box 3)
  - I.D.C. 101 (E.M. Lavalle), 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - I.D Course Spring, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Course Materials, 1972 (Box 3)
  - South Asia Book News Newsletter, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Enrollments, 1972 April (Box 3)
  - Budget Submission to Committee on International Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Enrollment, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Crauford D. Goodwin, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Finances: Correspondence with Treasurer, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence re: Grad Students, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Graduate Student Inquiries, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - IDC 101, Fall Semester, 1970 (Box 3)
  - IDC 102, Spring Semester, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Ford Proposal, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Monographs, Urbanization (Dr. Fox, #10), 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Monographs, Miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
  - IDC 102: Class File, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Finances: Correspondence with Treasurer, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Title VI, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Title VI Graduate Students, 1970 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Contract, 1970 (Box 3)
  - NDEA: Hew Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Center Proposal, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Technical Report, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Personnel Appointment Forms, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Visiting Lecturers IDC, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Visiting Lecturers: Public, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - AIIS, 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Association for Asian Studies: Mailing List and Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Association for Asian Studies: Newsletter, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Association for Asian Studies: Regional Meeting, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Advertising, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Affiliate Faculty: Addresses, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Announcements, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Book News, 1972 June-October (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Cavanaugh Proposal, 1971 (Box 3)
  - The Cellar Bookshop, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Committee on the Future of International Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Russell Dionne, circa 1970 (Box 3)
  - ID Course, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - ID Lecturers, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - I.D.C. 102 Syllabus, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - IDC 102 Class List, Assignments, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Graduate School, 1972 (Box 3)
  - India Seminar, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Inquiries, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Graduate Student Statistics, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Graduate Students Association, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Films and Filmstrips, 1969-1973 (Box 3)
  - Films, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Ford Proposal, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Finances General, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Finances: Telephone Bills, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Inquiries, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Enrollments, 1972; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Embree, Ainslie, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - S.A. Symposium on Education, 1971 (Box 3)